-What are you working on?
-Can't talk. In the zone.
-Do you know what he's doing?
-Could be anything.
Last time he was like this,
he figured out
electron transport in graphene.
The time before that,
he was making a list of who's allowed
in his tree fort if he ever gets one.
Still can't believe
I didn't make the cut.
Sheldon, you want to take a break?
Your food's ready.
No, what are you doing?
He's both happy and quiet.
It's like seeing a unicorn
and Bigfoot at the same time.
Sorry we're so late.
Bernadette got stuck at work.
Great news! A raccoon virus
just crossed the species barrier
and now can infect humans!
Why is that great news?
In the pharmaceutical business,
we have a saying:
"Mo' infections, mo' money."
Wait!
Maybe you want to wash
your little raccoon hands first.
Calm down.
If I had it, I'd be dead already.
Guys, listen up.
Can't listen, zone.
Also don't care.
Next week is the anniversary
of my first date with Bernadette.
Really don't care.
I want to do something special,
and I was hoping you guys
could be a part of it.
What horrible thing
are you trying to make up for?
Just putting something in the bank
for what horrible thing I do next.
Ah.
Look, she's gonna be back any second,
so here's the deal:
I'm writing a song, and hoping we
could all play it for her together.
-I love that.
-That is so beautiful.
Sheldon?
When did we get
to The Cheesecake Factory?
(THEME SONG PLAYS)
It's really sweet what Howard
wants to do for Bernadette.
Yeah. Hey, how come you've never done
anything romantic to celebrate our first date?
The Romance Resonance
Well, for starters, you've broken up
with me so many times,
which first date
are we talking about?
Whoa! Somebody call
the burn ward.
And back to the zone.
And besides, I do romantic things
for you all the time.
Can you even name one romantic thing
you've done for me?
-I can name tons.
-Sex doesn't count.
I know, what about
that bed-and-breakfast?
Well, I took you there.
All you did was...
I know what I did.
I bet they had to throw out
that rocking chair.
You know, I can be romantic
if I want to.
It's fine. And also not true.
Okay, just you wait and see.
I'm gonna romance
your freakin' ass off.
That's beautiful.
Is that Shakespeare?
-Sheldon?
-Zone.
He'll figure it out
when he falls off the roof.
Sheldon, I know you're in the zone,
but do you want some tea?
All right, I can't believe
I'm gonna say this, but
you haven't spoken in hours
and I'm starting to get worried.
Please say something.
Leonard, prepare to be humbled
and weep at the glory of my genius.
Nope, it was better before.
Look at it.
I feel like my mind just made a baby.
And it's beautiful.
It's not like human babies,
which are loud and covered in goop.
Holy crap, Sheldon,
did you just figure out a method
for synthesizing a new stable
super-heavy element?
Did I?
Well, that can't be right.
No one's ever done that before.
Except me, because I just did it!
Sheldon and his brain, yeah!
- Sheldon and his brain...
-Definitely better before.
So, I'm almost done
writing the song for Bernadette.
Are you cool playing the cello?
If by "cool"
you mean "willing to," yes.
If by "cool" you mean "cool,"
clearly you've never seen me
play the cello.
Great. Will you play the ukulele?
Of course. I'd be happy
to shred it on my ax.
Or you could just play your tiny,
ridiculous guitar.
Fine. I will melt her heart.
And her face!
Gentlemen.
No doubt you heard
about my little breakthrough.
Now, if your plan
is to hoist me on your shoulders
and carry me around the cafeteria,
please refrain.
I don't care for heights,
motion sickness
or the thought of your necks
touching my buttocks.
Seriously, congratulations, Sheldon.
Yeah, I read your paper online.
That technique for creating
a new heavy element is inspired.
Thank you.
Believe it or not,
I just learned
a Chinese research team
at the Hubei Institute
for Nuclear Physics
ran a test on a cyclotron,
and the results
were extremely promising.
Sheldon, that's incredible.
I know! They called it
the greatest thing
since the Communist party.
Although I'm pretty sure that the
Communist party made them say that.
I like China.
See, they know how
to keep people in line.
So, what happens next?
More testing,
more success, more fame.
But don't worry, I will remain
the same down-to-earth humble Joe
-I've always been.
-Good to know.
Now give me that cookie;
I discovered an element.
Thank you so much for coming.
You called the right person.
I believe I have the perfect romantic
evening for you to give Leonard.
Okay, good,
'cause I've been really struggling with this.
As I'm sure you're aware,
the quickest way to a man's heart
is through his...
Pants, but Leonard says
sex doesn't count.
Hm. You poor thing.
You have one arrow in your quiver,
and you just can't use it.
Fortunately, another pathway
to a man's heart
is through his stomach.
I don't know if I want to cook
for him; he's kind of a picky eater.
I mean, "It's too salty.
It's too dry.
It's too burnt and frozen
at the same time."
Wait, come on, what else
would sweep you off your feet?
Well, I've always had this fantasy
that involves dancing.
The sexual chemistry between
my partner and me is electric.
But boy, oh, boy,
does my father not approve
until he sees us
in the big dance competition.
Okay, that's just the plot
for Dirty Dancing.
What else would you love,
other than
being lifted
over Patrick Swayze's head?
Oh, oh. You could
stand outside his window
with a boom box in the air.
That's from Say Anything.
Look, I'm a lonely guy;
I watch a lot of movies.
Look, Penny,
if you truly want to be romantic,
it needs to come from you.
I get that, but why is this so hard?
Well, you've probably never had
to do this stuff 'cause you're young
and beautiful and men have
always thrown themselves at you.
Yeah, I'm trying to be sad
about that. I can't.
Let's see, what's next?
Okay! Here.
This is the Magic Marker
I was using
when I made the discovery.
I don't think the Smithsonian's
gonna want your marker.
And that's why you're not
on the list for my tree fort.
(CELL PHONE VIBRATING)
Ooh! Guess who's getting an article
written about him in Physics Today?
I'll give you a hint.
You measured the diameter
of his suspicious mole yesterday.
Sheldon, I'm so proud of you.
Well, you should be. My discovery
is spreading like wildfire.
Unlike my mole, which is holding
steady at the size of a navy bean.
What's next?
This is the very copy
of The Handbook
of Chemistry and Physics
in which I looked up the reaction
rates of mendelevium and....
-And what?
-No.
-No, no, no, no.
-What's wrong?
I've made a horrible mistake.
What are you talking about?
This table,
it's in square centimeters.
I read it as square meters.
You know what that means?
That Americans can't handle
the metric system?
Amy, I was off by a factor of 10,000.
But the Chinese team
found the element.
They shouldn't have.
My calculations were wrong.
There must be some resonance between
the elements I didn't know about.
So you just got lucky?
Sheldon Cooper does not get lucky!
You and me both, brother.
It doesn't matter.
The element was found because of you,
and that's groundbreaking.
What matters is
the greatest scientific achievement
of my life is based on a blunder.
I'm not a genius, I'm a fraud.
You know, Sheldon, in neuroscience,
we're forever finding something
in one part of the brain
that we thought was someplace else.
Great. Now I'm worse than
a fraud. I'm practically a biologist.
You got to stop beating
yourself up over this.
I mean, you made a mistake,
but it was a happy mistake.
There's nothing happy about it.
I'm being given credit
that I don't deserve.
People get things
they don't deserve all the time.
Look at me with you.
No, Leonard, this is going
to haunt me for the rest of my life:
every science classroom, every
periodic table, every textbook.
This mistake
will be staring back at me
Like that time you let Koothrappali
wax your eyebrows.
I've got to find a way
to stop this thing.
Buddy, I don't think you can. I mean,
once it's out there, it's out there.
This thing is like the science
equivalent of a sex tape.
Frankly, I'd prefer a sex tape.
You don't know
what a sex tape is, do you?
No.
Make sure you guys get
to the restaurant by 8:00.
Bernadette's
meeting me there at 8:30.
-I don't want to blow the surprise.
-We'll be there.
Got it. Now, I have
a question about the song.
I was thinking at some point
I could bust out a little rap.
Nah, nah, nuh, nuh, nuh, no.
Come on, come on,
you haven't even heard it yet.
Leonard, give me a beat.
I will not.
Please?
-No, I want this to be romantic.
-It will be!
I don't call anyone a ho,
and the only time
I use the phrase "my bitch,"
I'm referring to you.
MAN: There he is!
(APPLAUSE)
Stop it. Stop celebrating me!
Woo!
And no woos!
Not you, Dr. Woo, you're fine.
I want you all to know that
you have no reason to applaud me.
My so-called breakthrough
wasn't the result of my genius.
It was nothing more
than a boneheaded mistake.
So please refrain from praising me
for it in the future.
I don't understand.
They didn't find the element?
No, they found the element.
(APPLAUSE)
No, no, stop it!
I don't need to take this admiration
from the likes of you people!
-How do I make them stop loving me?
-Invite them to live with us.
Boy, Bernadette is gonna love this.
It must be nice to have someone
do something so romantic.
Okay, you know what's not romantic?
Rubbing it in someone's face.
Actually, it can be,
but I told you sex doesn't count.
I'm getting worried about Bernadette.
I'm gonna call and check on her.
The National Science Foundation
wants to give me a substantial grant.
-That's a big deal.
-I know.
When will this nightmare end?
Hey, I get that you feel bad about
all the attention,
but still, what you did is amazing.
We're really proud of you.
-I'm not.
-You're not?
Sheldon, I've been thinking about it,
and you're right,
you don't deserve any credit.
All you did was misread
some numbers on a table.
A very easy table, too.
Honestly, I'm embarrassed for you.
That's the most romantic thing
I've ever heard.
Damn it, everyone's
better at this than me.
Congratulations, Dr. Fowler.
You just made the fort.
Guys, there was an accident
at Bernie's lab.
My God, is she okay?
Yeah, but she's at the hospital
in quarantine.
-What?
-Poor Bernadette.
I hate to pile on the bad news,
but I just got a raise.
My God, Bernie, what happened?
Well, let's just say the next time
you move a dozen vials
of raccoon virus to the fridge,
make two trips.
You're sure you're okay?
Yeah, it's just a precaution.
If there was a problem,
I'd be throwing up
out of my eyeballs by now.
-Sorry I messed up our date.
-No, don't worry about it.
I brought the date here.
Guys, come on in.
What's all this?
Well, tonight is the anniversary
of our first date,
and I wanted to celebrate it
by writing a song for you.
Howie.
Sheldon, get over here!
She might be contagious.
Don't you think I'm having
a rough enough day?
Sheldon!
(PLAYING UPBEAT SONG
ON KEYBOARD)
If I didn't have you
Life would be blue
I'd be Doctor Who
without the TARDIS
Is it me,
or does she not look so good?
A candle without a wick
A Watson without a Crick
I'd be one of my outfits
without a dickey
I'd be cheese without the mac
Jobs without the Wozniak
I'd be solving
exponential equations
That use bases
not found on your calculator
Making it much harder to crack
I'd be an atom without a bomb
A dot without the com
And I'd probably still live
with my mom
And he'd probably still live
with his mom
Ever since I met you,
you turned my world around
You supported all my dreams
and all my hopes
You're like uranium-235
and I'm uranium-238
Almost inseparable isotopes
I couldn't have imagined
How good my life would get
From the moment
That I met you, Bernadette
Howie.
If I didn't have you
Life would be dreary
I'd be string theory
without any string
I'd be binary code
without a one
A cathode ray tube
without an electron gun
I'd be Firefly, Buffy and Avengers
without Joss Whedon
I'd speak a lot more Klingon
(SINGS IN KLINGON)
And he'd definitely
still live with his mom
Ever since I met you
you turned my world around
You're my best friend
and my lover
We're like changing electric
and magnetic fields
You can't have one
Without the other
I couldn't have imagined
How good my life would get
From the moment that I met you
Bernadette
We couldn't have imagined
How good our lives would get
From the moment that we met you
Bernadette
Howie, that was amazing!
Look, I'm shaking.
She's sick, I knew it. Bye!
I have to say, this is the best
Top Ramen you've ever made.
I discovered a secret ingredient:
the flavor packet.
That sucker is well named.
All right, lover boy, get ready,
'cause there is a crap storm
of romance coming your way.
Stop it, you're gonna make me cry.
(ROMANTIC MUSIC PLAYS)
All right, you seem pretty confident.
Oh, I am.
Maybe if you follow this trail,
you'll see why.
-Oh... Rose petals.
-Yes.
The most beautiful and shockingly
expensive of all the flowers.
You made the bed? You really
are pulling out all the stops.
Okay, I gave this a lot of thought,
and I finally found something
to show you how much I love you.
Oh, wow.
It's a first edition
of Hitchhiker's Guide to the Galaxy.
I remember it was your
favorite book growing up.
This is great.
Thank you... so much.
What?
Nothing. I love it.
No, something's going on.
What's wrong with it?
I remember you saying how great
it would be to have a first edition.
It's true, I did. I did say that...
...when we were at
the used bookstore together
and I saw the first edition
and I bought it.
Oh my God, I am the worst!
No, no, it's okay.
It's really thoughtful.
No, it's not! I mean...
What's thoughtful
is everything you do.
Here, you know what?
Look at this.
Look, here's the...
the plane ticket you bought me
when I was too poor
to go home for the holidays.
And the rose you left
on my windshield... just because.
Here's the thank-you letter
you wrote me
after the first time
I slept with you.
All 11 pages of it.
Can't believe
you saved all this stuff.
Of course I did. It's you.
Come here.
Is that a pregnancy test?
Just the first one.
I didn't save them all.
I can't believe
I read this table wrong.
I blame you.
Me? What did I do?
You distract me.
I've been distracted
since the moment I met you.
-Sorry.
-Well, you should be.
Because all I can think about
is how much I want to kiss you.
And not just on the cheek,
but on the mouth.
Like mommies and daddies do.
Oh, Sheldon.
SHELDON: Amy?
Amy? Did you hear what I said?
Can't talk, in the zone.